## Greetings I'm Michael Da Silva

(407) 300-4392 DevMichaelDaSilva@gmail.com programmedmikey.github.io

#### Skills

Extensive experience, extremely creative and highly efficient in web details, deep experience in web application development and management. Profound understanding of computer languages, as well as the principles and techniques of building and maintaining different sites and servers

## **Experience**

July 2020 - Aug 2021

#### **Vijilan Security, Orlando** - *Full stack developer (Contractor)*

- Integrated multiple third party software API's utilizing several technical tools that help monitor clients applications with Lumen as the main REST API framework for the integration.
- Multiple custom features in the custom Partner Portal(CRM) developed with PHP and JavaScript within Drupal CMS which is a platform for the clients to monitor their services, apps and customer service features.
- Ensured code quality in an Agile and SCRUM environment from home utilizing a test driven development approach.

Feb 2018 - March 2020

#### BuilderAll, Orlando - Full stack developer

- Completely designed and developed a fully dynamic and robust Email Marketing software named MailingBoss that went from 0 users to over 100 thousands concurrent users.
- Collaborated with Designers to create clean interfaces with intuitive interactions and simple but awesome experiences.
- Reinforced all dynamic and interactive Email Marketing software for a better user. experience and user interface, resulting in a tremendous increase in sales revenue.

Sept 2016 - Feb 2018

### MYGSPN, Clermont, Florida- Full stack Developer

 Project Coordination of Web Application Development, PHP programming, Angular 1, HTML, JavaScripts, Database Management (MySql, Microsoft SQL Server), systemic view on network and server administration, and deployment of security and encryption features in web applications May 2015 - Sept 2016

#### Villa Marketers, St.Cloud, Florida - Web developer

- Website design according to Accessibility, Web Interface Usability, XHTML, HTML and CSS code validation.
- Management on various websites using HTML / CSS, bootstrap, Java script, jQuery, PHP and MySQL.
- Preparation of functional specifications, mapping and monitoring software installation.
- Ensured site usability through implementation and Search Engine Optimization to improve results and business flow.

### **Education**

July 2012 - July 2016. Graduate

Florida Tech College, Orlando - Bachelors of Science in Computer Science

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

SENAI (Brazil) - System development course

# **Technology Experience**

- Nginx / Apache
- Web Security
- Web Sockets
- QA, Unit Testing
- NoSQL & MySQL
- Mongoose
- FTP, SSH & CPanel
- Terminal Usage
- Server Deployment
- Agile practitioner
- Functional & OOP design
- Rest API & MVC design
- Scaling and Optimizing

- HTML, CSS, PHP & JavaScript
- Angular1 & 2+
- Laravel & Eloquent
- React
- Drupal
- WordPress
- Next.js